<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Open Cloud Computing Interface - HTTP Header Rendering</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname>OCCI</firstname><surname>working
      group</surname></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>OGF</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
  </info>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Status of This Document</bridgehead>

  <para>This document provides information to the Cloud and Grid community.
  Distribution is unlimited.</para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Copyright Notice</bridgehead>

  <para>Copyright (c) Open Grid Forum (2009). All Rights Reserved.</para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Abstract</bridgehead>

  <para>This document is part of the Open Cloud Computing Interface (OCCI)
  specification document series. The OCCI document series describes what each
  OCCI compatible interface needs to provide. The overall OCCI specification
  itself is setup modular to be extensbible and includes the following
  parts:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The OCCI Core &amp; Models</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>The OCCI Infrastructure Models</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>OCCI XHTML5 rendering</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>OCCI HTTP Header rendering</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Each of these parts is described in a separate document so the overall
  specification comes in the form of a document series. Where as this document
  describes the OCCI HTTP header rendering. It can be seen as the machine
  interface for OCCI.</para>

  <para>All these parts and the information within are mandatory for
  implementors (unless otherwise specified).</para>

  <section>
    <xi:include href="occi-http.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/*/*)">
      <xi:fallback>
        <para>
          <emphasis>FIXME: MISSING XINCLUDE CONTENT</emphasis>
        </para>
      </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Contributors</title>

    <para>The following people have contributed to this document.</para>

    <table>
      <title>List of contributors</title>

      <tgroup cols="3">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry align="center">Name</entry>

            <entry align="center">Affiliation</entry>

            <entry align="center">Contact</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Andy Edmonds</entry>

            <entry>Intel - SLA@SOI project</entry>

            <entry>andy@edmonds.be</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Sam Johnston</entry>

            <entry>Australian Online Solutions</entry>

            <entry>samj@samj.net</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Thijs Metsch</entry>

            <entry>Sun Microsystems - RESERVOIR project</entry>

            <entry>thijs.metsch@sun.com</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Gary Mazzaferro</entry>

            <entry>OCCI Counselour - Exxia, Inc.</entry>

            <entry>garymazzaferro@gmail.com</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Intellectual Property Statement</title>

    <para>The OGF takes no position regarding the validity or scope of any
    intellectual property or other rights that might be claimed to pertain to
    the implementation or use of the technology described in this document or
    the extent to which any license under such rights might or might not be
    available; neither does it represent that it has made any effort to
    identify any such rights. Copies of claims of rights made available for
    publication and any assurances of licenses to be made available, or the
    result of an attempt made to obtain a general license or permission for
    the use of such proprietary rights by implementers or users of this
    specification can be obtained from the OGF Secretariat.</para>

    <para>The OGF invites any interested party to bring to its attention any
    copyrights, patents or patent applications, or other proprietary rights
    which may cover technology that may be required to practice this
    recommendation. Please address the information to the OGF Executive
    Director.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Disclaimer</title>

    <para>This document and the information contained herein is provided on an
    “As Is” basis and the OGF disclaims all warranties, express or implied,
    including but not limited to any warranty that the use of the information
    herein will not infringe any rights or any implied warranties of
    merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Full Copyright Notice</title>

    <para>Copyright (C) Open Grid Forum (2009). All Rights Reserved.</para>

    <para>This document and translations of it may be copied and furnished to
    others, and derivative works that comment on or otherwise explain it or
    assist in its implementation may be prepared, copied, published and
    distributed, in whole or in part, without restriction of any kind,
    provided that the above copyright notice and this paragraph are included
    on all such copies and derivative works. However, this document itself may
    not be modified in any way, such as by removing the copyright notice or
    references to the OGF or other organizations, except as needed for the
    purpose of developing Grid Recommendations in which case the procedures
    for copyrights defined in the OGF Document process must be followed, or as
    required to translate it into languages other than English.</para>

    <para>The limited permissions granted above are perpetual and will not be
    revoked by the OGF or its successors or assignees.</para>
  </section>
</article>
