<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Open Cloud Computing Interface - Use cases and requirements for a
    Cloud API</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname>Thijs</firstname><surname>Metsch</surname></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Sun Microsystems</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
  </info>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Status of This Document</bridgehead>

  <para>This document provides information to the Cloud and Grid community.
  Distribution is unlimited.</para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Copyright Notice</bridgehead>

  <para>Copyright (c) Open Grid Forum (2009,2010). All Rights Reserved.</para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect4">Abstract</bridgehead>

  <para>This document is an informal description of Use Cases and requirements
  for the OCCI Cloud API. Created by the Open Cloud Computing Interface
  working group. This document records the needs of IaaS Cloud computing
  managers and administrators in the form of Use Cases. The Use Cases serve as
  the primary guide for the development of API requirements. The document is
  the first deliverable to demonstrate and validate the features of the Open
  Cloud Computing Interface.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>This document includes all the Use Cases and requirements which were
    gathered in the working group.</para>

    <para>This document is organized in to three sections: Use Cases,
    Requirements and a comparison matrix of current Cloud APIs. In this
    document, Use Cases are defined by name and a set of functional and
    non-functional requirements. All requirements are categorized and
    formatted in tables. Each requirement is (whenever possible) mapped to a
    Use Case. Priorities have been assigned to all requirements. The Cloud API
    comparison matrix itemizes generalized and detail features of each API and
    indicates which API supports each feature.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <xi:include href="occi-usecases.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/*/*)">
      <xi:fallback>
        <para>
          <emphasis>FIXME: MISSING XINCLUDE CONTENT</emphasis>
        </para>
      </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
  </section>

  <section>
    <xi:include href="occi-requirements.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/*/*)">
      <xi:fallback>
        <para>
          <emphasis>FIXME: MISSING XINCLUDE CONTENT</emphasis>
        </para>
      </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
  </section>

  <section>
    <xi:include href="occi-feature-matrix.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/*/*)">
      <xi:fallback>
        <para>
          <emphasis>FIXME: MISSING XINCLUDE CONTENT</emphasis>
        </para>
      </xi:fallback>
    </xi:include>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusions</title>

    <para>The previous sections described to what extent Cloud requirements
    for an API exist. What is missing up to now is a general solution that
    fits most of the needs, is simple to implement, highly responsive
    (throughput), globally applicable (standard well known as well as dynamic
    connections), secure, highly recognized (commonly known and implemented)
    and last but not least standardized.</para>

    <para>This working group plans to use these Use Cases and requirements for
    the creation of an Cloud API.</para>

    <para>Similar work has been done in the Cloud Computing Use Case group.
    This document is published as the 'Cloud Computing Use Cases Whitepaper'.
    <xref linkend="CCUCW" /></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Contributors</title>

    <para>The following people have contributed to the requirements gathering
    and Use Case documentation.</para>

    <table>
      <title>List of contributors</title>

      <tgroup cols="2">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry align="center">Name</entry>

            <entry align="center">Affiliation</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Michael Behrens</entry>

            <entry>R2AD</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Richard Davies</entry>

            <entry>ElasticHosts</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Andy Edmonds</entry>

            <entry>Intel - SLA@SOI project</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Sam Johnston</entry>

            <entry>Australian Online Solutions</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Ignacio M. Llorente</entry>

            <entry>DSA-Research at UCM - RESERVOIR project</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Thijs Metsch (Editor)</entry>

            <entry>Sun Microsystems - RESERVOIR project</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Gary Mazzaferro</entry>

            <entry>OCCI Counselour - Exxia, Inc.</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>George Reese</entry>

            <entry>O'Reilly</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Luis Rodero-Merino</entry>

            <entry>Telefónica I+D</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Shlomo Swidler</entry>

            <entry>MyDrifts</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Tino Vázquez</entry>

            <entry>DSA-Research at UCM - RESERVOIR project</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Intellectual Property Statement</title>

    <para>The OGF takes no position regarding the validity or scope of any
    intellectual property or other rights that might be claimed to pertain to
    the implementation or use of the technology described in this document or
    the extent to which any license under such rights might or might not be
    available; neither does it represent that it has made any effort to
    identify any such rights. Copies of claims of rights made available for
    publication and any assurances of licenses to be made available, or the
    result of an attempt made to obtain a general license or permission for
    the use of such proprietary rights by implementers or users of this
    specification can be obtained from the OGF Secretariat.</para>

    <para>The OGF invites any interested party to bring to its attention any
    copyrights, patents or patent applications, or other proprietary rights
    which may cover technology that may be required to practice this
    recommendation. Please address the information to the OGF Executive
    Director.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Disclaimer</title>

    <para>This document and the information contained herein is provided on an
    “As Is” basis and the OGF disclaims all warranties, express or implied,
    including but not limited to any warranty that the use of the information
    herein will not infringe any rights or any implied warranties of
    merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Full Copyright Notice</title>

    <para>Copyright (C) Open Grid Forum (2009,2010). All Rights
    Reserved.</para>

    <para>This document and translations of it may be copied and furnished to
    others, and derivative works that comment on or otherwise explain it or
    assist in its implementation may be prepared, copied, published and
    distributed, in whole or in part, without restriction of any kind,
    provided that the above copyright notice and this paragraph are included
    on all such copies and derivative works. However, this document itself may
    not be modified in any way, such as by removing the copyright notice or
    references to the OGF or other organizations, except as needed for the
    purpose of developing Grid Recommendations in which case the procedures
    for copyrights defined in the OGF Document process must be followed, or as
    required to translate it into languages other than English.</para>

    <para>The limited permissions granted above are perpetual and will not be
    revoked by the OGF or its successors or assignees.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>References</title>

    <bibliolist>
      <biblioentry xreflabel="CCUCW" xml:id="CCUCW">
        <title>Cloud Computing Use Cases Whitepaper</title>

        <address><uri
            xlink:href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/17929394/Cloud-Computing-Use-Cases-Whitepaper">http://www.scribd.com/doc/17929394/Cloud-Computing-Use-Cases-Whitepaper</uri></address>

        <org>
          <orgname>Cloud Computing Use Case Discussion Group</orgname>
        </org>

        <date>2009-08</date>
      </biblioentry>
    </bibliolist>
  </section>
</article>
